So now we will see the concept of value blocks.
So value blocks are also data blocks, but they are special types of data blocks which you have to create
on your own.
We will see how we can create value blocks as well.
So value blocks are the blocks whenever you need integers in a form of increment or decrement.
Let's suppose you want to create an application where you want to store integers which will be increased
on certain condition and will be decreased on certain condition, like storing points or storing credit
values.
So these are all integers which can be increment or decrement as well.
Right.
So it depends on the condition it will be on the increment side and it can also be on the decrement
side, right?
So it depends on the condition you can use these value blocks.
So value blocks are created on any data block.
We can create value block on any data block and value block is of four bytes.
As you can see over here, the value block is of four bytes.
Then the same value block is repeated in the complement format.
Right.
So after four bytes, the starting from fourth till seventh byte, it's the complement of that bytes
of that integer, I mean to say.
So the value is stored in the first four bytes and then the complement of that integer.
Then again, this integer is repeated.
This is how value blocks work.
Right.
So this is how the structure of value blocks is created.
And the last four blocks are used to store the address of these three blocks.
Right.
So this is how value blocks work.
First, we create an integer of four bytes.
Then there is a complement of that integer.
And after the complement, the value is again repeated.
And then the address of the of these three blocks are in the last four blocks.
So this is how value blocks work.
We will see the application of value blocks practically in our coming videos.